Guide to the Thall and Lopez family papers and photographs CBHM.0022
Center for Brooklyn History
Thall and Lopez family papers and photographs
circa 1860s-1982
Center for Brooklyn History
Lopez, Laura V.
Lopez, Donald S., 1923-2008
Nottage, Muriel Thall, 1904-1979
Greene, William A., Lt. Col.
Thall, Jennie Greene
Thall, Charles Sewell, Dr.
CBHM.0022
0.7 Linear Feet in two boxes
Documents, ephemera and photographs relating to several generations of the Thall and Lopez families of Canarsie, Brooklyn.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to researchers without restriction.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Laura V. Lopez, 2023.
Arrangement
The documents are grouped into folders by family member or topic and arranged roughly chronologically. The photographs and ephemera are foldered separately.
Biographical note
Lt. Col. William Augustus Greene was born in Manhattan in 1840 and moved to Brooklyn at age 8, where he then resided for the rest of his life. He was a descendant of Robert Morris, a signer of the Declaration of Independence. He served in the United States Civil War as a member of the 173rd Regiment of New York Volunteers, during which he was wounded and captured multiple times. In 1872, he married Jane Williams (1847-1918), daughter of Charles Williams and Jane Vanderwenk. William and Jane Greene resided at 178 Clymer Street in South Williamsburg. William passed away in 1911.
Their daughter Jennie Greene (1873-1943) married Dr. Charles Sewell Thall (1872-1923) in 1901. Charles was the son of Richard Thall (1835-1905). The Thalls lived at 1122 East 92nd Street in Canarsie. Their son Sewell was born in 1906. Their daughter Muriel (1904-1979) married Hampton Nottage (1908-1961) in 1934. She worked at New York Bell. The Thalls' other daughter Lorraine (b. 1904) became pregnant by Puerto Rican shipwelder Carlos Santos Lopez, and their son Donald was born July 15, 1923.
Donald S. Lopez Sr. volunteered for the Army Air Forces Aviation Cadet Program in early 1942, after becoming interested in aviation in childhood partially because of his family home's proximity to Floyd Bennett Field on Jamaica Bay. He served as a United States Air Force fighter and test pilot and saw combat in both World War II and the Korean War. He retired from the Air Force in 1964. He spent eight years as an engineer on the Apollo and Skylab programs with Bellcomm, Inc., a subsidiary of Bell Labs. In 1972, he joined the staff of the National Air and Space Museum and served as a deputy director there until his death in 2008. He is buried with full military honors at Arlington National Cemetery.
Sources:
"Donald S. Lopez Sr." https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Donald_S._Lopez_Sr. Accessed January 22, 2024.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
If digital surrogates exist, they should be used in place of the originals whenever possible.
Related Materials
CBH holds many similar collections of family papers and photographs. In addition, these two collections contain some similar material as that in this collection:
United States, Confederate States, and foreign currency collection (1974.120)
Checks and receipts from Brooklyn businesses and institutions collection (CBHM.0014)
Scope and Contents
Letters, photographs, account ledgers, blue prints, wills, deeds, stock certificates, Civil War infantry manual, Civil War currency, notes, newspaper clippings, electrification contracts, assorted legal documents relating to the Thall and Lopez families of Canarsie, Brooklyn.
Canarsie (New York, N.Y.); Williamsburg (New York, N.Y.); Photographs; Correspondence; Tintypes (prints); Portraits; Studio portraits; Ledgers (account books); Blueprints; Albums; Mortgages; Mortgages -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Decedents' estates; Wills; Wills -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Decedents' estates -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Estates (Law); Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Veterans; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; Money -- United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; Lopez, Laura V.; Lopez, Donald S., 1923-2008; Nottage, Muriel Thall, 1904-1979; Greene, William A., Lt. Col.; Thall, Jennie Greene; Thall, Charles Sewell, Dr.
- Charles and Jane Williams and Jane Williams Greene, 1855, 1871 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- William A. Greene, circa 1860s-1911 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Scope and Contents
  Includes documents related to his Civil War service (including Civil War currency) and his interment at Greenwood Cemetery.
- William A. Greene's copy of "Infantry tactics", 1862 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- 178 Clymer Street, 1871-1920 (Box 1, Folder 3-5)
  Documents related to ownership of the property, specifications for building and work on the house, and blueprint plans of architectural details.
- Richard Thall, 1888-1905 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Jennie Greene Thall, 1901-1943 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Jennie Greene Thall account books, 1905-1908 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Charles S. Thall, 1905-1911 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Sewell S. Thall baptism certificate, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Muriel Thall Nottage, 1925-1966 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Includes correspondence, documentation of New York Bell stocks, and a marriage certificate.
- Katherine Greene stock certificates, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Documents stock held in the Belle Harbor Yacht Club.
- Genealogy notes and correspondence, circa 1975-1982 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Correspondence, genealogical charts and photocopied vital records connecting the Thall, Lopez, Greene and Williams family to the Brownells, O'Briens, Sewells and more. Traces the family lineage back to the Colonial period and beyond.
- Ephemera and clippings, circa late 19th-early 20th century (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Photographs, circa 1860s (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Mostly tintypes. Named individuals include C. Fowler Brennan (1868), G. Brasted (1862), Isaac Henry John Lakin (1867). Also includes a tintype made into a brooch.
- Photograph album, circa late 19th century (Box 2)
  Tintypes and cabinet cards in a leather album with gilded embossing and metal clasps. Named individuals include Jane Vanderwenk Williams, Charles Williams, William Augustus Greene, Jane Williams Greene, and Jennie Greene Thall.